So in conclusion, Sahaja Yoga meditation has a significant beneficial effect on your mental
Podsumowując, medytacja Sahaja Yoga ma znaczący, korzystny wpływ na umysł
and your physical health.
i zdrowie fizyczne.
So, to conclude, I've shown you that Sahaja Yoga meditation has a significant effect on
Pokazałam wam, że medytacja Sahaja Yoga ma znaczący wpływ na
the body, because it activates the parasympathetic nervous system and restores your bodily functions.
ciało, ponieważ aktywuje przywspółczulny układ nerwowy i przywraca funkcje organizmu.
It has an effect on the brain - it's a different state of consciousness, you activate areas
Ma wpływ na mózg – to inny stan świadomości, aktywują się obszary:
of attention, you activate the limbic areas which give you happiness, and you release,
uwagi, limbiczne, które dają szczęście i uwalniają się
good, happy, mood stabilising neurochemicals in your brain.
dobre, szczęśliwe, stabilizujące nastrój neurochemikalia w mózgu.
It prevents disease because it gives you better mental and physical health, it's a disease
Zapobiega chorobom, ponieważ zapewnia lepsze zdrowie psychiczne i fizyczne,
therapy, so if you have any illnesses you can use it to treat your illnesses through
więc jeśli masz jakieś choroby, możesz użyć jej do leczenia swoich chorób.
regular meditation, and as I showed you, it has an effect on a range of mental illnesses
Przy regularnej medytacji ma ona zbawienny wpływ na szereg chorób psychicznych
and physical illnesses.
i fizycznych.
And there has never been any negative effects, all the effects have always been positive.
I nigdy nie było żadnych negatywnych skutków, wszystkie efekty zawsze były pozytywne.
What is important as I said before, is the benefits associated with the state of mental
To, co jest ważne, jak powiedziałam wcześniej, to korzyści związane ze stanem ciszy psychicznej,
silence, so it's the mental silence which works.
więc działa cisza mentalna.
And nothing else.
I nic więcej.
So if you meditate, you have to try to achieve this state of mental silence as often as possible,
Jeśli więc medytujesz, musisz jak najczęściej starać się osiągnąć ten stan wyciszenia umysłu,
and that will be associated with better health at a mental and physical level.
a to będzie się wiązać z lepszym zdrowiem na poziomie psychicznym i fizycznym.
So, I think I've talked enough, and what we will do now is we'll have a meditation guided
Myślę więc, że powiedziałam wystarczająco dużo, a teraz zrobimy medytację prowadzoną
by the founder of Sahaja Yoga.
przez założycielkę Sahaja Yogi.
And if you follow my last slide we will go exactly there into the limbic system which
A jeśli śledzisz mój ostatni slajd, przejdziemy dokładnie do układu limbicznego, który
is here.
jest tutaj.
Which is also where the last slide is, and that's where we're going now.
Tam też znajduje się ostatni slajd i tam właśnie zmierzamy.
So you have heard about all the fantastic things which can happen to you, and hopefully,
Więc usłyszeliście o wszystkich fantastycznych rzeczach, które mogą wam się przydarzyć i mam nadzieję,
you feel today this mental silence.
ze poczujecie dzisiaj tę mentalną ciszę.
Where we're going to go now which is the Kingdom of God within.
Dokąd teraz pójdziemy, czyli do wewnętrznego Królestwa Bożego.
The Paradise within.
Raj wewnątrz.
Which you can have.
Które możecie mieć.
Here we go.
No to ruszamy.
And if you want to know more, there are a few web pages where you can read a bit more
A jeśli chcecie dowiedzieć się więcej, jest kilka stron internetowych, na których można przeczytać trochę więcej
about this Yoga.
o tej Jodze.